CHRISTIAAN SIMMONS

Plymouth, MN 55447

Phone: 773-290-4240 | Email: christiaan.simmons@live.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/christiaan-simmons-61116323 | Github: https://github.com/montechristiaan |

Portfolio: https://montechristiaan.github.io/UpdatedPortfolio/index.html

SUMMARY

User-focused Web Developer who enjoys taking on challenges and deadlines in high-stress situations. Adapting a successful career in live television production to provide "big picture" ideas for how users experience websites and apps.

A veteran producer of live television in markets like Las Vegas, Chicago, and the Twin Cities, I have covered every kind of breaking situation in real time and developed the ability to multi-task and problem-solve on the fly. I also saw projects through from start to finish on a daily basis, while successfully collaborating with teams and delegating responsibilities.

Currently enrolled in the Coding Boot Camp at the University of Minnesota gaining experience in web development technology utilizing HTML, CSS, Javascript, and jQuery. My goal is to share my passion for media and get back on the front line of developing and deepening the user experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL, node.js

Skills: APIs, Database management, AP style, Journalism

EDUCATION

Full Stack Coding Certificate: University of Minnesota Twin Cities, St. Paul, MN A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, node.js, SQL Databases, Mongo, Express, and React.

BA: English/Music: Augsburg University, Minneapolis, MN BA with a major in English Literature and a minor in Music Theory.

PROJECTS

Birthday Tracker | github.com/pbrayer/Project1 | pbrayer.github.io/Project1

- The Birthday Tracker app allows you to track as many birthdays as you wish, regardless of where you sign in, along with sending reminders as the big day approaches, and suggestion for gift ideas based on the interests of your friend or loved one.
- Lead contributor to overall front-end design, using html and css to interact with the javascript for functionality and to make a clean, useable website.
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, AJAX, Firebase, APIs.

TrashTaggers | github.com/petr0n/TrashTaggers | trashtaggers.herokuapp.com

- TrashTaggers allows the user to create, search, or join a list of cleanup groups from whichever area they choose. The app uses Google authentication for sign-up and MySQL and JAWSdb to store information.
- Lead designer on front-end, creating look and functionality from scratch so that back-end collaborators could easily identify what was needed.
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, AJAX, MySQL, JAWSdb, heroku, APIs, node.js, sequelize, mocha, chai, express, express-handlebars.

EXPERIENCE

Supervising Producer KARE11

2012 - 2017

Golden Valley,

MN

Key Accomplishments:

- Supervised a morning news broadcast from start to finish, with attention to every detail of the production.
- Oversaw three other producers who were each assigned a section of a two-and-a half hour daily newscast, checking their work for spelling, correct sources, and writing style.
- Responsible for assigning reporters their daily stories, or changing them in breaking news situations if need be.
- In constant contact with the on-air talent through an earpiece to make sure newscast ran smoothly as it was conceived.

Producer 2008 – 2012 **KSTP**

St. Paul, MN

Key Accomplishments:

- Planned, wrote, and executed a one-hour morning show daily.
- Wrote the show from start to finish, with an eye on every detail of each script.
- Chose the stories that went into each newscast, the order that they would go in, which anchor would read them, and the kind of camera shot the director should take.

Producer 2003 – 2008 **WFLD**

Chicago, IL

Key Accomplishments:

- Produced an hour of one of Chicago's most-watched morning news programs "Fox News in the Morning."
- Booking guests, producing segments for those guests, and making sure those guests had a
 pleasant experience on the show.
- Responsible for assigning reporters their daily stories, or changing them in breaking news situations if need be.

Producer KVBC

Las Vegas, NV

2001 - 2003

Key Accomplishments:

- Used a variety of different technologies, from ingesting and editing video on a digital platform to writing for the web.
- Produce an hour-long newscast each morning Monday through Friday.
- Monitor police scanners to make sure that I was covering any news breaking overnight.